Hey, what do you mean by
"destroying the Leaf Village"?
(ナルト)なぁ！ 木ノ葉を 潰すって
どういうことだってばよ!?
I mean today's Leaf Village!
(ヤマト)今の 木ノ葉をだ。
(サクラ)今の 木ノ葉を…。
Today's Leaf Village...?!
それじゃあ 綱手様を…！
That means, Tsunade-sama's will...!
そういうことだ…。
- You're right...
- What?
Your story doesn't add up.
さっぱり…
話が 見えねえってばよ。
I know Sai's boss used to
oppose Gramps Third,
いくら サイの上司ってのが➡
三代目の じいちゃんと
対立してたからって➡
but why do they have to destroy
the Leaf Village...
木ノ葉を 潰すとか➡
or do something
to Granny Tsunade?
綱手の ばあちゃんを
どうこうしようって➡
どうして なるんだよ!?
忘れたの？ ナルト。
Did you forget, Naruto?
綱手様は
三代目の 愛弟子だったのよ。
Tsunade-sama used to be
a favorite pupil of the Third.
そのうえ 五代目 火影➡
Besides that, the current regime of
the Leaf Village
綱手様を 中心とした
今の 木ノ葉の体制は➡
was initiated by
the Fifth Hokage, Tsunade-sama,
and it obviously complies with
the wishes of the Third.
明らかに 三代目の意志を
受け継いだものだ。
当然 ダンゾウとしても
おもしろくはないだろう。
Undoubtedly Danzo
is not happy about this...
かといって 里の ほとんどの者が
今の体制を 支持している以上➡
but most of the people in the village
support the current regime,
簡単に 体制が変わるはずもない。
so the regime
can't be changed easily.
この体制を 変えようと思ったら➡
The only way
to change the regime is...
to cause an earth-shaking event
in the village.
里全体を 揺るがすような
大事件でも 起こすしかない…。
An event like...
そう… 大蛇丸が仕掛けた➡
the "The Destruction of the Hidden Leaf Village"
that Orochimaru set up.
木ノ葉崩しのような事件をね…。
The destruction of
the Hidden Leaf Village...!
木ノ葉崩し!?
Danzo may be thinking about
conspiring with Orochimaru
もしも ダンゾウが 綱手様を
火影の座から 失脚させるために➡
and making him attack
Leaf Village one more time...
大蛇丸と 結託し➡
in order to force Tsunade-sama
from the position of Hokage...
もう一度 木ノ葉を襲わせようと
考えているのだとしたら…。
それだけのために
木ノ葉を 潰すっていうのかよ！
So, you're saying they want
to destroy Leaf Village...
- just because of that?!
- It's not only because of that!
(サクラ)それだけじゃない！
体制の崩壊後
自分が理想とする 里をつくり➡
He wants to build his ideal village
after destroying the regime...
and return to center stage as Hokage.
火影として
再び 表舞台に立つためよ！
くっ…！
The reason why Danzo went into
action at this late date is...
今になって
ダンゾウが 動き出したのは…。
...because he sees it's been three years
since the last attack,
前回の 木ノ葉崩しから
３年 経って➡
so there has been enough time
for Orochimaru...
大蛇丸側の戦力も➡
to fully regain his forces.
十分 整った頃だと
にらんだから…。
I think that's also part of it.
それも あるだろうが➡
Or he may have thought
Orochimaru is more cautious now
大蛇丸が 前回の襲撃失敗で
より 慎重になっている…➡
because of the failure
of the last attack.
と 考えたからかもしれない。
If he acts now, he thinks
the negotiations with Orochimaru...
今なら 大蛇丸との交渉も
容易に進む… とね。
will get under way easily.
That means he's going to propose
cooperation from the village, right?
里の中から 協力すると
持ちかけるわけですね？
…そうだ。
Yes...
まさか…。
Wait a minute...
You mean Sai's secret mission is...
じゃあ… サイの極秘任務って…。
おそらく…。
Perhaps...
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
The Consequences of Betrayal
じゃあ… サイの極秘任務って…。
You mean,
Sai's top secret mission...
(サクラ)おそらく…
大蛇丸に取り入って➡
...is probably to earn Orochimaru's trust
ダンゾウとのパイプ役に なること…
だったのかも…。
and serve as a liaison between
Danzo and Orochimaru.
私たちの班にいれば➡
He thought the odds of him
running into Orochimaru...
大蛇丸と 接触できる確率が高いと
考えた…。
would be high
if he was in our group.
そんな…！
That can't be...!
事と次第によっては…➡
If that's the case...
サイを 始末しなければ
ならないかもしれない。
then we might have to get rid of Sai.
始末…！
Kill him?
(カブト)大蛇丸様…。
Orochimaru-sama.
(大蛇丸)わかってる…。
I know.
(大蛇丸)つけられてるわね…。
It appears we're being followed.
単純に 後を つけられたか➡
Is he simply following us,
or is someone making him do that?
それとも グルか…。
どうします？
What should we do?
One way or the other...
(大蛇丸)どちらにしても➡
１つ 死体が
必要じゃないかしら。
I'm afraid we're going
to need a corpse.
ねぇ… カブト。
Right, Kabuto?
フフフフ…。
フッ…。
《サイを…》
Kill...
《始末って…➡
...Sai?
いくらなんでも
そんなあっさり…》
No matter how you look at it,
that's too hasty...
Now, my clone is
following them,
(ヤマト)今 ボクの分身が
ヤツらを追っているが➡
but there's no way of knowing
what's gonna happen...
何が起きるかわからない。
We're gonna get on their trail
right away.
ボクらも すぐに あとを追うよ。
- But...
- Okay!
でも…！
わかった！ よ～し！
Let's go...!
行くってばよ…。
あ… あれ？
What the...?
Naruto!
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto! Are you all right?
ナルト 大丈夫？
ハァ ハァ… うっ…！
《まだ さっきのダメージが
抜けきってないんだ》
He hasn't fully recovered yet from
the damage he suffered earlier...
ヤマト隊長。
Captain Yamato...
Sakura, we better get going...
サクラ 急ごう。
確かに…➡
I know we should catch up
right now. But...
すぐ追いかけたほうがいいのは
わかります。 けど…。
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
But... with Naruto's condition
being like this...
けど ナルトが こんな状態では…。
In that case, we'll leave him.
(ヤマト)だったら
ナルトは 置いていくよ。
Leave him? No way...!
《置いてくって そんな…》
He should have
enough strength left...
そんな状態でも １人で里に帰る
力くらいは 残ってるでしょう。
to get back to the village
on his own.
カカシ先生なら そんな言い方！
Kakashi-sensei would never
talk that way...!
サ… サクラちゃん…。
Sakura-chan...
サクラちゃん… オレなら…➡
I'll... be... all right...
大丈夫だってば… よ…。
行けるってばよ… ヘヘ… ぐっ！
I can make it...
ナルト！
くっ…。
Naruto!
サクラ キミの言いたいことは
わかってるつもりだ。
Sakura, I know
what you're trying to say.
そのうえ ボクは➡
On top of that, I've teamed up with Kakashi-san
in the Anbu Black Ops Unit before...
カカシさんと
暗部で組んだこともある。
あの人が
どういう人かも知ってる。
I also know the kind of person he is.
確かに ボクは カカシさんの代理だ。
It's true that I'm filling in
for Kakashi-san.
けど カカシさんと ボクは違う。
But, I'm not Kakashi-san.
ハァ ハァ… ハァ ハァ…。
キミたちを 傷つけやしないよ…。
I'm sorry, but I just can't say,
"I won't let you get hurt"
with a laugh.
なんて
笑って言うのは ごめんだよ。
I won't let my comrades die.
((カカシ : オレの仲間は 絶対
殺させやしないよ))
キミたちは もう守られるだけの
見習い忍者じゃないし➡
You're no longer apprentice Ninja
in need of protection,
いずれ カカシさんを
超えてかなきゃならない➡
but Shinobi shouldering
the future of the Leaf Village...
木ノ葉を担う忍びだ。
who will have to eventually
surpass Kakashi-san.
慈悲と甘えは違う。
Compassion and co-dependence
aren't the same thing!
ここで あきらめたら終わる。
If we give up now,
it'll end in failure.
今 追わなきゃ 二度と
大蛇丸は 捕まえられない。
If we don't follow now,
we're never going
to catch Orochimaru.
大蛇丸相手に
二度もチャンスはないんだよ。
There is no second chance
with Orochimaru.
サクラちゃん…。
Sakura-chan...
うん…。
Yeah.
では すぐに行動開始だ。
ナルト… キミはどうする？
It's time to get moving now.
Naruto, what are you going to do?
ヘッ… もちろん…。
Of course...
I'm going!
行くってばよ！
Naruto!
ナルト！
I'm okay...
大丈夫…。
If I went back to
the village now...
ここで里に帰ったら…。
I wouldn't know
why I came this far.
何のために ここまで来たか
わかんねえってばよ！
ナルト…。
Naruto...
Fine, but...
if you slow us down,
いいだろう。
だが 少しでも
遅れるようであれば➡
we have to leave you behind,
do you understand?
容赦なく見捨てていくからね。
Okay!
おう！
じゃあ いくよ！
Then, let's go!
あれは…！
That's!
《やってくれるね… 大蛇丸》
You've sure done it...
Orochimaru...
ナルト！
Naruto!
サクラちゃん！
Sakura-chan!
サクラちゃん…。
Are you all right, Sakura-chan!
大丈夫か？ サクラちゃん。
その傷は…？
That wound is...
《ヤマト : 九尾のチャクラが 毒のように➡
Chakra of the Nine-Tailed Fox
must have entered...
傷口から入り込んでしまったに
違いない…》
through the wound like poison...
This can't easily be healed even
with a skilled medical Ninjutsu.
《ヤマト : あれは優れた
医療忍術をもってしても➡
簡単には治せない…》
That's why...
《だからこそ… だからこそ➡
That's why I'm even more surprised
あのチャクラに耐えている
ナルトが驚きなんだ》
that Naruto has been able
to endure that Chakra.
This...
これは…。
This... was done by Orochimaru.
(サクラ)これは… さっき
大蛇丸に やられたの。
でも 少し痛むだけだから 大丈夫。
Well, it hurts only a little, so...
I'm okay.
Don't push yourself
too hard, Sakura-chan.
あんまり ムリすんなってばよ
サクラちゃん…。
…うん。
I got it...
Let's take a little break.
ここで少し休憩しよう。
サクラは この隊 唯一の医療忍者。
Sakura is our team's
only Medical Ninja...
いわゆる任務成功の要だからね。
In other words, she is a key cog
in the success of our mission.
大丈夫です！
すぐにでも出発しなきゃ…。
I'm all right.
If we don't leave now...
さっき ヤマト隊長だって…。
even you said...
I'm sorry... but I just can't say,
((キミたちを傷つけやしないよ…
なんて➡
"I won't let you get hurt"
with a laugh.
笑って言うのはごめんだよ。
You're no longer apprentice Ninja
in need of protection,
キミたちは もう 守られるだけの
見習い忍者じゃないし➡
いずれ カカシさんを
超えてかなきゃならない➡
but Shinobi shouldering
the future of the Leaf Village...
who will have to eventually
surpass Kakashi-san.
木ノ葉を担う忍だ。
(慈悲と甘えは違う))
Compassion and co-dependence
aren't the same thing!
It's true what I said,
確かに さっきは
ああ言ったけど➡
but they also say that
"haste is from the devil".
急いては事をし損じる…
ともいうでしょ。
急ぐのと ムチャするのとは
違うってことさ。
I mean, there is a difference between
hurrying and recklessness.
そうそう！
I agree!
Captain Yamato is right!
ヤマト隊長の言うとおりだってばよ。
You are the only Medical Ninja
in our group
サクラちゃんは この隊 唯一の
医療忍者で➡
with brutish strength...
怪力なんだからさ。
So, you're the most vital
part of the group!
大事な要っていうことだ。
I told you that you don't need
to add "brutish strength"!
だから 怪力を
増やすなっつってんだ！
- What, what?!
- Shut up!
ちょっ 待て なんで…。
(サクラ)うるさい！
I'm just complimenting your...
オレはサクラちゃんを
ほめてるだけで…。
O-Okay, okay...
I apologize!
わかった！ 謝るってばよ！
Naruto!
(ヤマト)ナルト。
Since Sai's out, you'll be
my partner for the battle.
サイが抜けた以上 戦闘では
ボクとバディを組むよ。
今のうちに
連携のパターンを決めておこう。
Let's decide on our collaboration
patterns while we have time.
Can you come over here
for a bit?
少し こっちへ来てくれ。
Got it.
わかったってばよ。
うっ…。
They stopped the chase...
I wonder if it went well...
追跡は止まったわね。
うまくいったかしら？
Perhaps...
(カブト)おそらく…。
At any rate...
それにしても➡
you did a fine job, as usual, Kabuto...
いつもながら
鮮やかな手際ね…カブト。
I've created countless dead bodies
since I've been with you, Orochimaru-sama...
大蛇丸様と一緒にいるおかげで➡
今までも 数限りなく
死体を作ってきましたからね。
It might have been
a little wasteful, though...
少し もったいなかったかも
しれないけど…。
それでも用心に
こしたことはありませんからね。
Even so, it's better to be cautious.
そうだ…
いい考えがありますよ 大蛇丸様。
Oh.
I got a good idea,
Orochimaru-sama.
ん？
あの子にも 実験を
手伝わせたら どうでしょう？
How about having him help out
our experiments?
I think he'll have lots of free time...
ダンゾウとのパイプ役以外は
暇になるでしょうしね…。
besides serving as
a liaison with Danzo...
フッ… 好きにしなさい。
Hmm... do as you please.
(ヤマト)やっぱりニセの死体か…。
A fake body, just as I thought...
Most likely this Jutsu
was done by Kabuto...
おそらくは カブトの術…。
Sure enough, this wound
is slow to heal...
《思ったとおり
この傷は 治りがおそい。
痛みをやわらげるのが精一杯ね》
the best I can do is
to ease the pain...
This is far enough...
《この辺りでいいかな…》
We're gonna do it here?
ここでやるのか？
あぁ。
Yes...
But, first...!
だが まずは…。
One moment, my Wood Clone
has just contacted me.
ちょっと待ってくれ…
ボクの木分身から連絡が入った。
Yes... That's right...
あぁ そうだ… 頭に
不自然な縫い目がうっすらとある。
There's an unnatural and subtle
stitching in the head...
He's done a perfect job,
it's not noticeable at first glance.
ひと目では 見逃してしまうほどの
完璧な仕上がりだ。
If we didn't prepare for this,
あの仕込みがなければ
騙されていた。
we would have been fooled
completely...
Amazing that they've already discovered
that we've been tailing them.
追跡が もうバレてるとはねぇ。
I was confident, but...
自信はあったが
これからは さらに慎重にいくか。
we have to be even more cautious
from now on...
ん？
Since we're dealing
with Orochimaru...
《大蛇丸が相手だ…。
we can't be too careful.
慎重すぎるくらいで
ちょうどいいかもな…》
Captain Yamato!
ヤマト隊長！
あぁ!!
Ah yes, I'm done with my errand.
こっちの用件は済んだ。
All right! So, what are
we gonna do first?
よし！ まずは どうするんだ？
But before that...
There's something I need to tell you.
と その前に…。
キミに言っておかなきゃ
ならないことがある！
The one who hurt Sakura was...
サクラを傷つけたのは➡
キミだよ！ ナルト。
you, Naruto.
ハァハァ… ハァハァ…。
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
sora wa haruka
kumo wa nagarete
Far, far, far away,
beyond the horizon.
tooku tooku tooku
ni kogaretemo
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
doko o mezashite boku
wa fumidasu no ka
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
mayoi o ima
furikitte
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
nigeba no nai
unmei demo
I'm searching
for tomorrow.
asu o sagashite
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
(ヤマト)木ノ葉縦断 スーパークイズ！
Your prayer will
be granted,
motomeru nara
woah woah
さぁ 始まりました
本日のチャレンジャーは この方たちです。
Because the light
you seek lies there.
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
よっしゃ！
しゃ～んなろ～！
それでは 波の国編から
早押しクイズ！
Awaken the
beast within!
mezamero
yasei
(ヤマト)タヅナを護衛するため
波の国へと向かった➡
Hmph,
It's you...
At last,
they meet again.
Finally.
カカシ班の前に
立ちふさがった➡
Next Episode
霧隠れの鬼人の
異名をもつ忍といえば…。
Hey Sakura-chan, is that the picture book
that belonged to Sai?
Yes, it is.
再不斬！
I'm wondering what's
in the book?
Don't ask me.
(ヤマト)ですが 再不斬に拾われ➡
Hmm, it seems there're
no words or dialogue, though.
彼の忠実な道具として
生きることに意味を見いだした➡
Well, even if we see what's inside,
I bet It's not good at all.
血継限界をもち
魔鏡氷晶という術を使う➡
I'm hoping this book gives some
information leading to Sai...
女の子のような顔をした
忍といえば…。
Come to think of it,
Sai cherishes this book, doesn't he?
白！
(ヤマト)ですが 彼らを雇って
タヅナたちによる橋の建設を➡
He also said it's
his older brother's book.
Hey, don't you think the facing pages are a little creepy?
妨害していた
ガトーのボディーガードといえば…。
The Unfinished Page
そんなヤツいたっけか？
まったく覚えてない。
Next Time: "The Unfinished Page"
Leaf Crossing Super Quiz!
"Leaf Crossing Super Quiz"
(ヤマト)おっと ここでタイムアップ！
正解は…。
Here it comes.
Today's challengers are these people!
"Host Yamato"
(２人)そんなのわかるか！
"Uzumaki Naruto"
Okay!
"Haruno Sakura"
Shannaro!
"Sai"
"Hatake Kakashi"
Fastest-fingers-first quiz from
the Land of the Waves arc!
While escorting Tazuna
to the Land of the Waves,
Team Kakashi was hindered by a shinobi
from the village of the Hidden Mist
also known as
"The Demon of The Hidden Mist"...
Zabuza!
Not finished yet!
This shinobi was picked
up by Zabuza.
He found a purpose in life
by fighting as Zabuza's faithful servant.
And has a Kekkai Genkai
that uses the Ice Crystal Ice Mirrors.
He has feminine facial features...
Haku!
Not finished yet!
Who are the Gato's bodyguards,
and were used to disrupt
Tazuna's bridge construction?
Were there such guys?
i don't remember at all.
"Taka & Toshi"
Oh, oh times up!
The answer is: Waraji and Zori!
— How can we know such a lame answer!